Business Ephemera Collection
Hartford History Center, Hartford Public Library
Business ephemera collection
1840-Present
Hartford History Center, Hartford Public Library, Hartford, Connecticut
3.81 cubic feet (11 boxes)
The collection includes billheads, letterheads, calendars, paper bags and boxes, trade cards and other forms of printed matter documenting Hartford businesses, including banks, insurance companies, and stores, from the mid-nineteenth century through the present day.
Historical Note
Ephemera is a collective term for different kinds of printed paper items that were originally meant to be discarded after use. Examples include advertisements, calendars, menus, paper bags, and posters. While these items were produced for a specific purpose and were not intended to be collected or preserved, people frequently save items that hold special meaning for them. They also save items that they perceive to be of historical significance. Collections of ephemera are a valuable historical resource that can provide unique insights into the period in which the materials were created. The items in the ephemera collection in the Hartford History Center have been donated by many different individuals over the years and the collection continues to grow through donations and purchase.
Scope and Content
This collection contains different forms of printed paper items produced by Hartford businesses beginning in the 1840s and continuing through the present. Many types of ephemera, such as trade cards and catalogs, functioned solely as advertising. Others, such as bookmarks, calendars, and blank books, might serve a useful purpose as well as providing advertising for a firm. Much of the ephemera, especially the earliest items, were printed locally by Hartford’s many printing firms. Later items were often, though not always, printed elsewhere.
Access Restrictions
The records are stored in a restricted area and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Accruals
The collection is closed. Additional accruals are not expected.
Subject Headings
Corporate Names
Aetna Insurance Company; Bingham & Dodd; Brown, Thomson & Company; Connecticut Mutual Life Insurance Company; G. Fox & Company; Hartford Chemical Company; Hartford Fire Insurance Company; Hartford Public Library; Kellogg & Bulkeley; Smith, Northam & Company; Travelers Insurance Companies; William Wander & Son; Williams & Carleton
Subjects
Advertising; Banks; Booksellers and bookselling; Department stores; Dressmakers; Drugstores; Grocery trade; Hatters; Hotels; Industries; Insurance companies; Jewelers; Millinery; Music stores; Opticians; Printers; Restaurants; Shoe stores; Stores, Retail; Tailors
Geographic Terms
Hartford (Conn.)
Genre Terms
Advertising cards; Billheads; Business cards; Calendars; Correspondence; Letterheads; Menus; Paper bags
Geographic names
Hartford (Conn.)
Contents:
- Banking and Insurance
  - Letter, Aetna National Bank, 1873; Letter to Anthony Burnham from A. R. Hillyer regarding a deposit (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Check, American National Bank, 1900-1909; Blank check (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Check, Bank of Hartford County, 185-; Blank bank check printed by E.B & E.C. Kellogg (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Check, Bank of Hartford County, 1857; Check for $1100 signed by Porter & Co. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Check, Bank of the United States, 183-; Blank check (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter, Charles Denison Banker and Broker, 1902; Notice of receipt of check (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual report, Charter Oak Bank and Trust Company, 1973; Statement of changes in capital accounts, statement of changes in allowance for possible loan losses (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brochure, Connecticut Bank and Trust Company, 1970; "Career Opportunities at CBT" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brochure, Connecticut Bank and Trust Company, 1970s?; "A Conversation about Custody--and its result" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brochure, Connecticut Bank and Trust Company, 1972; "Mortgage Loans" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brochure, Connecticut Bank and Trust Company, 197-?; "The Revocable Living Trust" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brochure, Connecticut Bank and Trust Company, 197-?; "The Duties of an Executor" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brochure/Statement, Connecticut River Banking Company, 1931; "105 Years of Service" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Check, Connecticut River Banking Company, 1893; "Check for $21.92 made out to "Geo. Avery" by H. Maercklein" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Check, Connecticut River Banking Company, 1894; "Check for $17.18 made out to "Geo. Avery" by the Connecticut River Banking Company" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Advertising logo, Connecticut River Banking Company, 1900; Original artwork in three colors depicting vessels on the Connecticut River (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brochure, Connecticut Savings Bank, 1971; "Thank you for banking with us…." (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Notice of stockholders meeting, Exchange Bank, 1864; Notice of a meeting on March 29, 1864 to consider becoming a National Bank (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Statement, Farmers and Mechanics Bank, 1831; "Lists assets of $1,373,244.23 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agreement, Farmers and Mechanics Bank, 18--; Conditions of loans from bank (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Check, Farmers and Mechanics Bank, 184-; Blank bank check printed by Elihu Geer (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Check, Farmers and Mechanics Bank, 1859; Check for $607.33 signed by Porter & Co., printed by E.B. & E.C. Kellogg (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual report, First Connecticut Bancorp, 1973; First Connecticut Bancorp, Inc. was a holding company; its subsidiaries were United Bank & Trust Company (Hartford), New Britain National Bank, The Simsbury Bank and Trust Company, and Pioneer Credit Corporation (Great Barrington, Massachusetts). (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter, First National Bank, 1941; Letter from Warren S. Archibald, South Church, enclosing a check (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter, First National Bank of Hartford, 1946; Check from Poly Choke Company for withholding tax enclosed (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter, First National Bank of Hartford, 1941; Letter from Atlas Underwriters Agency regarding fire insurance policy for property of Melba I. and Joseph R. Donovan (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter, Geo. P. Bissell & Co., Bankers, 1864; Letter to Wm. M. Stanley regarding a lawsuit (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brochure, George P. Bissell & Co., 1871; Description of services (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Depositor's book, George P. Bissell & Co. Bankers, 18--; Covers of bank book (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Check, George P. Bissell & Co. Bankers, 187-; Blank check (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Check, Hartford Bank, 183-; Five blank checks (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brochure, Hartford Federal Savins, 1970s?; Advertisement for First National City Travelers Checks (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Financial statement, Hartford Federal Savings, 1973; Statement of condition, list of offices and hours (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Coin folder, Hartford Federal Savings, 197-?; Folder holding twenty quarters: "Every quarter you save counts for you." (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Home improvement loan application, Hartford Federal Savings, 1971?; Postage paid folder with information and application form (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brochure, Hartford National Bank and Trust, 1973; "Managing your Investments… in the way best suited to your needs" (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter, Merchants and Manufacturers' Bank, 1863; Letter to W. Webster concerning relief of debts (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Check, Park Street Trust Company, 1922; Four checks (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Promissory note, Phoenix Bank, 182-; Two blank promissory notes on a single sheet (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bill of exchange, Samuel Talcott, 1764; Bill of exchange made out to George Wyllys (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Auditor's report, Society for Savings, 1852; Lists amounts deposited and withdrawn, cash in hand, balance due (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Auditor's report, Society for Savings, 1840; Lists amounts deposited and withdrawn, cash in hand, balance due (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Annual report, Society for Savings, 197-; Brochure listing activities, statement of condition, statement of earnings, officers, and trustees (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ATM envelope, Society for Savings, 1991; Deposit, payment, or check reorder envelope (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Brochure, Society for Savings, 1972; Brochure in Spanish: "Servicios bancarios individuales" (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Depositor's book, South end Bank and Trust Company, 1951-1958; Bank book of James J. Laughlin, in plastic case (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Brochure, Union Trust, 1971; "Duties of an Executor" (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Brochure, Union Bank and Trust Company, 1970s?; "The 'pour-over' will and trust linking life insurance and your will" (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Advertisement, United States Security Trust Company, 1926; Three illustrated rack cards featuring Nathan Hale, Benjamin Franklin, and Patrick Henry (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Brochure, Aetna Casualty and Surety Company, 1944; "Use and Care of Hand Tools" (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Policy, Aetna Casualty and Surety Company, 1972; Automobile insurance policy of Beverly A. Loughlin (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letter, Aetna Insurance Group, 19--; Corrected letterhead for "F. Sidney Holt" (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Advertisement, Aetna Fire Insurance Company, 19--; Card of L. Norman Zafros, Red Lion, Pennsylvania, Insurance and Real Estate Agent (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Insurance card, Aetna Life and Casualty Company, 1972?; Blank card with information on whom to call in case of an automobile accident (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Appointment, Aetna Life Insurance Company, 1871; Appointment of Samuel Camp, M.D. as Medical Examiner at Great Barrington (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Advertisement, Aetna Life Insurance Company, 1863; Lists premiums for life insurance (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Policy, Aetna Life Insurance Company, 1947?; Sample life insurance policy (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Receipt, Aetna Life Insurance Company, 1917; Receipt for Liberty Loan Bond subscription payment (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Notice, Charter Oak F. & M. Insurance Company, 1858; "Please observe carefully the suggestions made below with reference to certain policies issued at your Agency…." (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Statement, City Fire Insurance Company, 1859; Lists assets and liabilities (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Annual statement, Connecticut Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1861; Includes information and advertising (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Annual statement, Connecticut Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1863; Includes information and advertising - 2 copies (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Annual statement, Connecticut Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1864; Includes information and advertising - 2 copies (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - List, Continental Life Insurance Company, n.d.; List of persons residing in Hartford and vicinity who have recently been insured (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letter, Continental Life Insurance Company, 1878; Letter to F. H. Curtiss stating that "this company is not about to fail… " (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Envelope, F.A. Thompson, General Agent, 1894; Envelope addressed to Delano P. Parkhurst, Danielson, Conn. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Certificate of insurance, Hartford County Mutual Fire Insurance Company, 1838; Renewal certificate granted to Joseph North (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Certificate of insurance, Hartford County Mutual Fire Insurance Company, 1844; Renewal certificate granted to Sylvester Champion (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Policy, Hartford County Mutual Fire Insurance Company, 1897; Policy covers house, farm buildings, livestock, hay and grain (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Semi-annual statement, Hartford Fire Insurance Company, 1871; Lists cash in hand, interest, loans, investments (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Appointment, Hartford Fire Insurance Company, 1868; Appointment of George Tilden as agent and attorney for the company in Keene, New Hampshire (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Envelope, Hartford Fire Insurance Company, 1894; Envelope addressed to George Palmer, Agent, Branford, Conn. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Statement, Hartford Fire Insurance Company, 1881; Lists assests, capital, outstanding claims (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Card, Hartford Fire Insurance Company, 1882; Card listing assets and naming Origen S. Acee, Agent, Gainesville, Fla - 3 copies (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Advertisement, Hartford Fire Insurance Company, 18--; "A Record! Over Twenty-three Million dollars have been paid to beneficiaries and policyholders of the Hartford Life Insurance Co. of Hartford, Conn." (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Magazine, Phoenix of Hartford Group of Insurance Companies, 1954; Centennial issue of The Phoeconeq (Vol. 4, No. 2) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Invoice, Putnam Fire Insurance Company, 1869; Invoice for insurance made out to D. Beach (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Policy, Travelers Insurance Company, 1942; Accident policy issued to Helen F. Davis (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Identification card, Travelers Insurance Company, 1900; Blank card, envelope, and protective enclosure (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Advertisement, Travelers Insurance Company, 19--; Envelope advertising accident insurance for railroad and steamship passengers (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Printing and Publishing
  - Subscription form, Review and Telegraph, 1838; The Review and Telegraph was in business from 1828 to 1838. (Box 2)
  - Receipt, Hartford Times, 18--; Receipt for payment of subscription (Box 2)
  - Receipt, Hartford Times, 1897; Receipt for payment of subscription to the Daily Times (Box 2)
  - Receipt, Connecticut Courant, 1847; Receipt for payment for a one-year subscription (Box 2)
  - Subscription form, John C. Wells, 184-; Receipt for subscription to thirteen magazines (Box 2)
  - Receipt, The Hartford Printing Company, Elihu Geer Sons, 1919; Receipt for a copy of Geer's Hartford City Directory, September 1919 (Box 2)
  - Advertisement, Park Publishing Company, 188-?; Full-page advertisement soliciting agents to sell a projected book on "Stanley in Africa" (Box 2)
  - Advertisement, Horace King, 187-?; Full-page advertisement for the book "Ireland of Today" by M.F. Sullivan (Box 2)
  - Advertisement, Dustin, Gilman & Company, 1876?; Full-page advertisment soliciting agents for "Guarding the Mails, or Secret Service in the United States Post-office Department" by P. H. Woodward, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Advertisement, Winter & Company, 1886?; Full-page advertisement for the book "Guarding the Mails, or Secret Service in the United States Post-office Department" by P. H. Woodward (Box 2)
  - Letter, Winter & Company, 1886; Form letter to newspaper seeking to place advertisement for "Secret Service of the Post-Office Department" by P.H. Woodward in exchange for a copy of the book (Box 2)
- Calendars
  - Calendar, Phoenix Insurance Company, Hartford, Conn., 1882 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Calendar, E.W. Kenyon and Company, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Phoenix Mutual Life Insurance Company of Hartford, Conn., 1902 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Thomas Oakes & Sons, 1908; "Monthly reminder" (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Connecticut River Banking Company, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Mark Twain Calendar, 1921; Published by George Sully and Company, New York (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - John's Delicatessen, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1935 Calendar commemorating the Three Hundredth Anniversary of Hartford, Conn., "Copyright 1934 TheTravelers Insurance Company" (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - International Market, Inc., 1940; "Compliments of Mrs. Maria Rubera." Illustration is Holy Family with dove, in silver foil frame. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Florence Gift Studio & Doll Hospital, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Case, Lockwood & Brainard Company, 1945; Illustration is a reproduction of Morton Hansen's wood-engraving of First Church of Christ in Farmington (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Fichera's General Store, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - South Congregational Church, 1952; Dr. Warren Archibald pictured on the front (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Connecticut Printers Incorporated, 1965; Illustration is a reproduction of Morton Hansen's wood-engraving of First Church of Christ in Farmington (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Connecticut Printers Incorporated, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Hartford National Bank and Trust Company, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Gift calendar for 1776, 1976; Distributed by Sage-Allen Pharmacy, Main Street, Hartford. Photographed at Henry Ford Museum and Greenfield Village, Detroit, Michigan. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Hartford National Bank and Trust Company, 1979; 3 copies (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Arthur A. Watson & Co., Inc., 1980; Includes old photographs of Hartford and Wethersfield (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bob Steele's 1982 Connecticut Calendar, Copyright 1981 by Spoonwood Press, Ltd., P.O. Box 3153, Hartford, Conn. 06103. Photographs by Jack McConnell. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Lux Bond Green & Stevens Fine Jewelers, 1982; Wedding anniversaries, holidays, and birthstones listed on back (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Vintage Hartford 1985, Published by Memorabilia, 10 Evergreen Square, Somerville, Massachusetts. Photographs are from the Library of Congress. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Society for Savings, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Old State House 2001 Calendar, Illustrations are reproductions of wood-engravings by Morton Hansen. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Menus
  - Menu, 32nd Restaurant, Lunch Menu (yellow) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Menu, 32nd Restaurant, Breakfast menu (white) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Menu, 32nd Restaurant, Breakfast menu (yellow) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Menu, 32nd Restaurant, Dinner menu (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Menu, 32nd Restaurant, Lunch menu (white) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Menu, 32nd Restaurant, Menu cover (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Place mat, 32nd Restaurant, Place mat (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Guest receipt, 32nd Restaurant, Guest receipt (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Menu, 36 Lewis Street, Dinner menu (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Menu, 36 Lewis Street, Midday menu (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Aetna Restaurant and Shipwreck Lounge (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Al-Di-La Restaurant (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Aqui me Quedo, Two separate sheets with menus in Spanish and English (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Arch St. Pizza (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Arch Street Tavern (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Arts Café (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Boccaccio's, Donna and Ron Salerno, proprietors (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Brown, Thomson & Company, Food and Drink Emporium (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Brownstone, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Capitol Fish House, Blue Ocean, Inc., 1992?; Includes sheet with "Tonight's Specials" (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Menu, Caravan Inn (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Menu, Carbone's, Recipe for Petti di Pollo Parmigianan (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Menu, Cloister Restaurant, 1976? (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Menu, Cloister Restaurant, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Menu, Cornerstone Deli (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Menu, Downtown Hunan Pavilion (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Menu, Frank's Restaurant, 1974? (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Menu, Galleria Café, "Overlooking the Old State House" (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Menu, Harry's Place of Colchester (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Menu, Honiss Oyster House Co., "Established 1845" "The Oldest Eating Place in Hartford" (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Menu, Honiss Oyster House, "Established 1845" (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Menu, Honiss Oyster House, R. Judd Campion, Richard W. Dennison, Proprietors; Chef de Cuisine, William W. Salamites, 1976 A.R.O.C. chef of the year (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Menu, Il Capriccio, Celebrated 25 years in 1991. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Menu, J.P.'s Fun food & Drink, 2 copies (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Menu, L'Americain, According to the Hartford Courant, "located in a crime-plagued area of the South End." (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Menu, Last National Bank, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Menu, Last National Bank, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Menu, Last National Bank (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Menu, Marble Pillar Restaurant, "Established 1860" (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Menu, Marble Pillar Restaurant, Wednesday, July 31, 1968; "Minimum of 25 cents per person from 12 to 2 and 5 to 7" (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Florence Gift Studio & Doll Hospital, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Menu, Metro Diner, G. Fox (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Menu, Municipal Café (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Menu, Municipal Cafeteria, 1952; Also listed as "Nicolas Cafeteria" in Price & Lee Directory (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Menu, No Fish Today (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Menu, Paris Croissant (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Menu, Parkview Hilton (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Menu, Quiche n'Kettle, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Menu, Restaurante Costa del Sol, "Spanish Mediterranean Cuisine" (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Menu, Rising Sun Restaurant (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Menu, Rising Sun Restaurant, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Menu, Russian Lady Café (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Coaster, Russian Lady Café (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Menu, Scoler's Restaurant and Cocktail Lounge, 1978?; "Hartford's Finest Restaurant Since 1932" "A Family Tradition" (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Menu, Shenanigans, Lunch (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Menu, Shenanigans, Lunch and Dinner (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Menu, Sheryl's, "A Unique Pita Bread Sandwich" (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Menu, Sign of the Green Kettle Luncheon and Tea Room (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Menu, Signature Restaurant, 1975-1981; Closed in 1981 "after six years" (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Menu, Skywalk, Opened in 1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Menu, Taverno Numero Cento (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Menu, Telli's Deli (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Menu, The Lobster, "Hartford's Smartest Cabaret Restaurant" (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Menu, The Times (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Menu, The Times, Includes autograph notations (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Menu, Town Sun Restaurant (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Menu, Upper Crust (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Menu, Wine Loft, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Paper Bags and Boxes
  - Bag, Brown Thomson, Large brown bag with handle. Text reads "BT's / Brown Thomson's / Hartford's Friendly Department Store." (Box 6)
  - Bag, G. Fox & Co., Small brown paper bag (Box 6)
  - Bag, G. Fox & Co., Large blue-gray bag, folded (Box 6)
  - Bag, G. Fox & Co., Large blue bag with handle (Box 6)
  - Bag, G. Fox & Co., Large maroon bag, folded (Box 6)
  - Box, Sage-Allen, Box, poor condition (Box 6)
  - Bag, Sage-Allen, Large bag, folded (Box 6)
  - Bag, Sage-Allen, Brown bag with daisy design (Box 6)
- Billheads, Invoices, Letterheads, Receipts
  - Advertisement, [No name], 19--; Announcement of sale of bankrupt stock of "a large wholesale clothing store in New York" to take place in Hartford (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Receipt, A.C. Hine Company, 1960; Invoice for 1957 De Soto sedan sold to Henry L. Creelman (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Receipt, A.M. Collins & Co, 1833; Receipt for Blue Cloth purchased by Mr. Bronson (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Receipt, Aetna Stamp Works, 1896; Invoice for a stamp made out to the Unitarian Church (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Invoice, Allen & Willard, 1867; Invoice for one Webster Furnace made out to M. L. Filley (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Invoice, Barnard's Express Line, 1875; Invoice for moving furniture, chairs, table, "stuff" made out to Mr. Hammersley (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Writ, Beach & Ward, 1797; Writ requiring payment of $340.98 to Beach & Ward by Norman Butler (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Advertisement, Bee Hive, 1884; Sheet music issued by the Bee Hive printed with advertisement for holiday goods and useful presents (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Receipt, Benjamin Bliss & Company, 1870; Invoice for mittens, calico, gras de Zurich, wool, mohair, braid, thread, etc. made out to Estate of Ira Hills (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Advertisement, Brown & Gross, 185-?; Advertisement for Brown & Gross attached to an illustrated flier for A. J. Downing's Landscape Gardening (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Receipt, Brown, Thomson & Company, 1888; Receipt for shirt, vest, netting, etc. purchased by W. N. Kirtland (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Invoice, Brown, Thomson & Company, 1890; Invoice for 10 yards of C.D. Goods purchased by Warner, Clark & Taylor (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Invoice, Brown, Thomson & Company, 1887; Invoice for fabric purchased by Warner & Clark (Box 7, Folder 2)